如果一个光子打向有两个狭缝的平面
So if a photon is directed through a plane
如果有一个狭缝可以观测到
with two slits in it and either slit is observed,
那它没有同时通过两个狭缝
it will not go through both slits.
如果观测不到  那它会通过
If it's unobserved,it will.
但如果它是在离开平面后
However,if it's observed after it's left the plane
在击中目标物之前被观测到
But before it hits its target,
那它不会同时通过两个狭缝
it won't have gone through both slits.
没错  你想说什么
Agreed. what's your point?
没什么  我只是觉得这个主意放在T恤上不错
There's no point,I just think it's a good idea for a t-shirt.
东西容器 必属精品
添加微信公众号：ABContainer 获取更多剧集
-您好  -稍等
-excuse me. -hang on.
横1是"爱琴海"
One across is "aegean."
竖8是"纳巴科夫"(1899-1977  俄裔美国小说家)
Eight down is "nabokov."
横26"MCM"
26 across is "mcm."
竖14是...你手挡住了...
14 down is... move your finger...
是"门"(生物分类)  所以说横十四是"太子港"(海地首都)
"phylum" which makes 14 across "port-au-prince"
你看  "Papa Doc"(海地总统绰号)提示了  所以是"太子港"
See,"papa doc's capitol idea," that's "port-au-prince."
在海地
Haiti.
-需要帮忙吗  -是的
-can I help you? -yes.
这里是高智商精子库吗
Is this the high-iq sperm bank?
如果这还要问的话  那你可能不该来这
If you have to ask,maybe you shouldn't be here.
我看就是这儿了
I think this is the place.
-把表格填了  -谢谢
-fill these out. -thank you.
-马上就好  -不急
-we'll be right back. -take your time.
我正好把填字游戏做完
I'll just finish my crossword puzzle.
等等
Oh,wait.
莱纳德  我觉得我做不到
Leonard,I don't think I can do this.
开什么玩笑  你都是"半职业选手"了
What,are you kidding? you're a semi-pro.
不是的  我们这是在犯基因欺诈罪
No. we are committing genetic fraud.
我们的精子并不能保证
There's no guarantee that our sperm
将来就能生出高智商的后代
is going to generate high-iqOffspring.
你想想  我姐姐和我的DNA结构相同
Think about that. I have a sister with the same basic dna mix
可她只是快餐店的女服务生
Who hostesses at fuddruckers.
谢尔顿  当初是你要来的
Sheldon,this was your idea.
这点补贴能让我们
A little extra money to get
在寓所里拥有分式T-1带宽
fractional t-1 bandwidth in the apartment.
我知道  我的确渴望更快的下载速度
I know,and I do yearn for faster downloads.
但那些可怜的女人们
But there's some poor woman
会把希望寄托在我精子上的
who's gonna pin her hopes on my sperm.
如果她最后发现那小不点连曲线下面积
What if she winds up with a toddler who doesn't know if he should use
该用积分还是微分算都不知道  她会怎么想
An integral or a differential to solve the area under a curve?
-我肯定她还是会爱他的  -我不会
-i'm sure she'll still love him. -i wouldn't.
你现在想怎么样
Well,what do you want to do?
我想走了
I want to leave.
该怎么跟她说呢
What's the protocol for leaving?
我不知道...我以前从来没在捐献精子时中途走人过
I don't know... I've never reneged on a proffer of sperm before.
我们就直接走吧
Let's try just walking out.
-再见  -再见  很高兴见到你
-bye. -bye. nice meeting you.
你还在为那个精子库的事生气吗
Are you still mad about the sperm bank?
没有
No.
你想不想听有关楼梯的有趣事情
You want to hear an interesting thing about stairs?
不太想
Not really.
如果有一格阶梯的高度存在哪怕两毫米的微小差距
If the height of a single step is off by as little as two millimeters,
-大多数人会被绊倒  -跟我无关
-most people will trip. -i don't care.
两毫...那不太可能吧
Two milli... that doesn't seem right.
不  是真的  我12岁时做过一系列试验
No,it's true,I did a series of experiments when I was 12
我爸爸还摔断了锁骨
My father broke his clavicle.
你就是因为这个被他们送去寄宿学校的?
Is that why they sent you to boarding school?
不是  是因为我那些关于激光的试验
No. that was a result of my work with lasers.
这是新邻居?
New neighbor?
很明显
Evidently.
比起上一个的水准真是有显著提高
Significant improvement over the old neighbor.
那个体重200磅有皮肤问题的异装癖者?
200-pound transvestite with a skin condition?
那是  没错
Yes,she is.
-你好  -你好
-oh,hi. -hi.
我们不想打搅你  我们就住你对面
We don't mean to interrupt. we live across the hall.
你们真好啊
Oh,that's nice.
我们不是住在一起  我是说...
We don't live together. I mean...
我们是住在一起
We live together,
不过是在分开的  异性恋的卧室里
But in separate,heterosexual bedrooms.
好的
Okay,well...
看来你们就是我的新邻居了  我叫佩妮
Guess I'm your new neighbor. penny.
-我是莱纳德  他是谢尔顿  -你好
-leonard. sheldon. -hi.
那么...
Well...
欢迎成为我们的邻居
Welcome to the building.
谢谢你  我们可以什么时候喝喝咖啡
Thank you. maybe we can have coffee sometime.
很好啊
Great.
-那...再见  -再见
-well... bye. -bye.
我们要不要请她来吃午饭?
Should we have invited her for lunch?
不  我们要开始看太空堡垒卡拉狄加第二季
No.We're gonna start season two of battlestar galactica.
第二季的DVD我们已经看过了
We already watched the season two dvds.
但评论音轨还没看
Not with commentary.
我觉得我们应该做个好邻居
I think we should be good neighbors
请她作客  让她觉得亲切
And invite her over,make her feel welcome.
我们从没请过那个叫路易还是叫路易斯的过来
We never invited louie-slash-louise over.
那是我们的不对
And that was wrong of us.
我们得扩大下我们的朋友圈子
We need to widen our circle.
我的朋友圈子已经很大了
I have a very wide circle.
我的空间上有212个好友
I have 212 friends on myspace.
不错  可他们你一个也没见过
Yes,and you've never met one of them.
这正是其美妙之处
That's the beauty of it.
我要请她过来
I'm gonna invite her over.
我们可以好好吃一顿  然后...聊天
We'll have a nice meal and... chat.
聊天?  我们平时不聊天  至少下了网不聊
Chat? we don't chat. at least not offline.
这没什么难的
It's not difficult.
你只要听着她讲些什么
You just listen to what she says
然后你适当地回应她一些
And then you say something appropriate in response.
那最后要干什么?
To what end?
你好...又来了
Hi... again.
你好
Hi.
那个...
Anyway...
我们带了印度菜回来
We brought home indian food.
然后...
And...
我知道搬家可能会很累
I know that moving can be stressful,
并且我发现当我身心俱疲时
And I find that when I'm undergoing stress,
美食和伙伴能让我感觉很舒坦
That good food and company can have a comforting effect.
还有  咖喱本身有通便功效  我想我不必再说
Also,curry is a natural laxative,and I don't have to tell you
你知道  如果大肠通畅...
That,you know,a clean colon is just...
那又可以少一件操心事了
One less thing to worry about.
这方面我不在行  不过我相信如果是邀请别人吃午餐
I'm no expert,but I believe in the context of a luncheon invitation,
你最好不要说些肠运动的事
You might want to skip the reference to bowel movements.
你们是在邀请我过去吃饭?
You're inviting me over to eat?
是的
Yes.
你们真好  我很乐意
Oh,that's so nice. I'd love to.
太好了
Great.
你们平时都玩些什么
So,what do you guys do for fun around here?
今天我们尝试过靠自慰来挣钱
Today we tried masturbating for money.
《生活大爆炸》
第一季  第01集
Pilot
好了  就当在自己家一样
Okay,make yourself at home.
谢谢
Thank you.
不用谢
You're very welcome.
这些东西看上去真深奥啊
This looks like some serious stuff.
-莱纳德  这是你写的?  -不  这是我的
-leonard,did you do this? -actually,that's my work.
不错  只是一些量子力学而已
Yeah. well,it's just some quantum mechanics
边上还随便写了一点点弦理论
With a little string theory doodling around the edges.
那部分  是我开的玩笑
That part there,that's just a joke.
讽刺下波恩-奥本海默近似
It's a spoof of the born-oppenheimer approximation.
这么说  你就像是"美丽心灵"里那种天才一样
So you're like one of those beautiful mind genius guys.
是吧
Yeah.
-真让人赞叹  -我也有块板
-this is really impressive. -i have a board.
如果你喜欢板  这块是我的
If you like boards,this is my board.
上帝啊
Holy smokes.
如果你说"上帝啊"是想
If by "holy smokes",you mean
再一次强调说你能在任何一个麻省理工的
A derivative restatement of the kind of stuff
男生寝室墙上发现那些涂鸦  那一点没错
You can find scribbled on the wall of any men's room at mit,sure.
-什么?  -得了吧
-what? -come on.
谁没看到那微分上面写着"我打住了  心碎了  算不下去了"
Who hasn't seen this differential below "here I sit,broken-hearted"?
至少我不会为了解决个数学问题
At least I didn't have to invent 26 dimensions
去发明个什么26维出来
Just to make the math come out.
我没有创造发明  他们本来就有
I didn't invent them. they're there.
-哪个宇宙有?  -所有的都有...这就是我说的关键
-in what universe? -in all of them... that is the point.
你们介意我先开吃吗
Do you guys mind if I start?
佩妮...
Penny...
这是我的座位
That's where l sit.
那  你坐我旁边
So,sit next to me.
不...我坐那里的
No... I sit there.
有什么区别
What's the difference?
-什么区别?  -开始了
-what's the difference? -here we go.
在冬天  这个位子离暖气比较近所以比较暖和
In the winter,that seat is close enough to the radiator
但也不至于太近以至于引起出汗
To remain warm,and yet not so close as to cause perspiration
在夏天  通过窗子吹进来的风直接在这里交叉
In the summer,it's directly in the path of a cross-breeze
就是这边和那边的窗户
Created by opening windows there and there.
看电视正好有个角度
It faces the television at an angle
不会太正  从而影响跟别人说话
That is neither direct,thus discouraging conversation,
也不会太斜  从而造成脖子酸疼
Nor so far wide as to create a parallax distortion.
我还能继续  不过我觉得你已经明白我的意思了
I could go on,but I think I've made my point.
你想让我移开吗
Do you want me to move?
你就随便坐一下吧
-well... -just sit somewhere else.
好的
Fine.
谢尔顿  坐下!
Sheldon,sit!
这样很好啊
Well,this is nice.
不太有人来我们这里作客的
We don't have a lot of company over.
不是吧  库萨帕里和沃尔维茨就经常过来
That's not true. koothrappali and wolowitz come over all the time.
-是  我知道  但...  -星期二晚上
-yes i know,but... -tuesday night,
我们还玩"克林贡拼字游戏"玩到凌晨一点(克林贡是外星人)
We played klingon boggle till 1:00 a.m.
是  我记得
Yeah,I remember.
-不要说我们没有伙伴  -对不起
-don't say we don't have company. -sorry.
-这是社交上很消极的暗示  -我说对不起了
-that has negative social implications. -i said I'm sorry!
"克林贡拼字游戏"?
Klingon boggle?
是的  就是普通的拼字游戏  只不过...
Yeah. it's like regular boggle,but...
是用克林贡语言
In klingon.
关于我们已经说得够多了  说说你吧
That's probably enough about us. so,tell us about you.
我?  好吧
Me? okay.
我是射手座的
I'm a sagittarius,
就这一点你们很可能就了解得比我想说的多得多了
Which probably tells you way more than you need to know.
没错  我们可以了解到你有群众性文化妄想
Yes. it tells us that you participate in the mass cultural delusion
就是指你出生时
That the sun's apparent position
相对于任意确定星座的太阳的视位置
Relative to arbitrarily defined constellations at the time of your birth
可能会决定你的性格
Somehow affects your personality.
有什么来着?
Participate in the what?
我认为谢尔顿是想说
I think what sheldon's trying to say
我们可能不会第一个猜你是"射手座"的
Is that sagittarius wouldn't have been our first guess.
是  很多人会以为我是水相星座的
Yeah,a lot of people think I'm a water sign.
还有什么  让我想想
Okay,let's see,what else.
我是素食者  但我吃鱼
I'm a vegetarian. except for fish.
偶尔吃牛排  牛排真赞!
And the occasional steak. I love steak!
真有趣
Well,that's interesting.
莱纳德吃玉米会不消化
Leonard can't process corn.
你有什么工作吗
Well... do you have some sort of a job?
有  我是家乳酪蛋糕店的服务生
Yeah. I'm a waitress at the cheesecake factory.
我很喜欢乳酪蛋糕
I love cheesecake.
你不是不能吃乳糖嘛
You're lactose-intolerant.
我是不吃...我只是觉得那东西不错
I don't eat it... I just think it's a good idea.
还有  我正在写一个剧本
Anyways,I'm also writing a screenplay.
讲一个多愁善感的女生从内布拉斯加州的林肯来到了洛杉矶
It's about this sensitive girl who comes to l.a. from lincoln,nebraska,
她本想当名演员  最终却在乳酪蛋糕店当了服务生
To be an actress and winds up a waitress at the cheesecake factory.
看来这是根据你的经历写的
So,it's based on your life.
不  我是来自奥马哈
No,I'm from omaha.
如果真拍成了电影  我会去看的
If that was movie,I would go see it.
我就说  是不错吧?
I know,right?
让我想想  还有什么...
Okay,let's see,what else...
大概就这些了
Guess that's about it.
这就是佩妮的故事了
That's the story of penny.
真不错
It sounds wonderful.
是不错
It was.
直到我爱上了那混蛋!
Until I fell in love with a jerk!
怎么回事?
What's happening?
上帝  你知道吗  我和他同居了4年
God,you know,4 years I lived with him.
整整4年...都跟高中生涯一样长了
4 years... that's like as long as high school.
你花了4年才读完高中?
It took you 4 years to get through high school?
真...不敢相信我竟然那么信任他
It just... I can't believe I trusted him.
我该说些什么吗?  我感觉我该说些什么
Should I say something? I feel like I should say something.
你?  算了  你只会越帮越忙
You? no,you'll only make it worse.
你们想知道最悲哀的是什么吗
You want to know the most pathetic part?
即使我已经恨透了他的谎言  他的不忠
Even though I hate his lying,cheating guts...
我还是爱他
I still love him.
我是不是疯了?
Is that crazy?
是疯了
Yes.
不  不是的  这只是...
No,it's not crazy. it's a...
只是一种悖论
It's a paradox.
自然界中到处都存在着悖论  比如说光
Paradoxes are part of nature. think about light.
按照惠更斯的理论  光是一种波
If you look at huygens,light is a wave,
双缝实验证明了这一观点
As confirmed by the double-slit experiments,
不过后来有了爱因斯坦
But then along comes albert einstein
他发现光原来也具有粒子性
And discovers that light behaves like particles,too.
我至少没越帮倒忙
Well,I didn't make it worse.
我真的很抱歉  我真是一团糟
I'm so sorry. I'm such a mess.
最糟的是  我搬家都搬得恶心死了
On top of everything else,I'm all gross from moving
没想到该死的淋浴器还不能用了
And my stupid shower doesn't even work.
我们的可以用啊
Our shower works.
真的?  如果我在这里洗你们会不会介意?
Really? would it be totally weird if I used it?
-会  -不会
-yes. -no.
-不会  -不会
-no. -no.
就在那边
It's right down the hall.
谢谢
Thanks.
你们真是太好了
You guys are really sweet.
这番进步有意思啊
Well,this is an interesting development.
怎么?
How so?
上次有个女人在我们这里轻解罗裳
It has been some time since we've had a woman
距离现在已经很久了
Take her clothes off in our apartment.
不见得啊  记得感恩节
That's not true. remember at thanksgiving,
我那老年痴呆的祖母上演的那段?
My grandmother with alzheimer's had that episode?
明白了  距离上次有女人
Point taken. it has been some time
在我们这里轻解罗裳  并且看了之后
Since we've had a woman take her clothes off,
我们不想把眼睛给挖出来的  已经很久了
After which we didn't want to rip our eyes out.
其实最糟的是看她切那火鸡
The worst part was watching her carve that turkey.
你现在究竟是要干些什么呢
So what exactly are you trying to accomplish here?
你说什么?
Excuse me?
那女人不会跟你上床的
That woman is not going to have sex with you.
我没有想要跟她上床
I'm not trying to have sex with her.
那就好  这样你就不会失望了
Good. then you won't be disappointed.
你凭什么认为她不会和我上床了
What makes you think she wouldn't have sex with me?
我是男的  她是女的
I'm a male and she's a female.
没错  但不是同一物种
Yes,but not of the same species.
我才不跟你讨论什么假设
I'm not going to engage in hypotheticals here.
我只想当个好邻居
I'm just trying to be a good neighbor.
是啊
Of course.
那也不是说如果有机会可以发展肉体关系
That's not to say that if a carnal relationship were to develop,
我会袖手旁观
That I wouldn't participate.
大致是这样
However briefly.
当她发现你的卢克·天行者(星球大战人物)无泪洗发水
Do you think this possibility will be helped or hindered
你说这种可能性是会变大了呢还是变小了
When she discovers your luke skywalker no-more-tears shampoo?
那是达斯·维德(另一星战人物)牌洗发水
It's darth vader shampoo.
卢克·天行者是护发素
Luke skywalker's the conditioner.
-先看这个  -太强了  难以置信
-wait till you see this. -it's fantastic,unbelievable.
看什么?
See what?
1974年  史蒂芬霍金在麻省理工的演讲
It's a stephen hawking lecture from mit in 1974.
现在不是时候
This isn't a good time.
那时他还不是这样毛骨悚然的电脑音
It's before he became a creepy computer voice.
-不错  可你们现在必须得走  -为什么
-that's great. you guys have to go. -why?
现在不是时候
It's just not a good time.
莱纳德有女士来访
Leonard has a lady over.
是的  我明白了...你祖母又回城来了?
Yeah,right... your grandmother back in town?
不是  她不是什么女士  她是新来的邻居
No. And she's not a lady. she's just a new neighbor.
等等  这里真的有位女士?
Hang on,there really is a lady here?
你赶我们走是为了想要和她交媾?
And you want us out because you're anticipating coitus?
我没有想要和她交媾
I'm not anticipating coitus.
那就是说别人现在可以和她交媾?
So she's available for coitus?
我们可不可以不要说"交媾"这个词了
Can we please just stop saying "coitus"?
更精确的说法应该是"体外射精"
Technically,that would be"coitus interruptus. "
是不是应该有个旋关把水从浴缸那里弄到淋浴器上
Hey,is there a trick to getting it to switch from tub to shower...?
不好意思  大家好
Hi. sorry. hello.
很高兴认识您  女士
Enchant? mademoiselle.
我是霍华德·沃尔维茨  加州工学院应用物理系学生
Howard wolowitz,caltech department of applied physics.
我的一些研究成果你可能已经很熟悉了
You may be familiar with some of my work.
它正在围绕着木星的最大卫星轨道运行
It's currently orbiting jupiter's largest moon
拍摄高分辨率的数码照片
Taking high-resolution digital photographs.
我是佩妮  我在乳酪蛋糕店工作
Penny. I work at the cheesecake factory.
我带你去弄那旋关吧
I'll show you the trick with the shower.
"Bonne douche"
Bonne douche.
你说什么?
I'm sorry?
是法语里"洗个痛快澡"的意思
It's french for "good shower. "
是一句祝词  我能用六种语言来说
It's a sentiment I can express in six languages.
还是留着博客上说吧  霍华德
Save it for your blog,howard.
洗个痛快澡
好了  没问题了  是卡住了  不好意思
All right,there it goes. it sticks. I'm sorry.
-好的  谢谢  -不用谢
-okay,thanks. -you're welcome.
你只要站在...  好吧  我...
You're just gonna to step right... okay,I'll...
-等等  莱纳德  -洗头的那些东西都是谢尔顿的
-hey,leonard? -the hair products are sheldon's.
我能让你帮个忙吗
Can I ask you a favor?
帮个忙?
A favor?
当然  你可以让我帮你忙  我可以帮你个忙
Sure,you can ask me a favor. I would do you a favor for you.
你如果不愿意也没关系
It's okay if you say no.
我应该会愿意的
I'll probably say yes.
一般你刚认识某个人  不会请求一件这样的事
It's just not the kind of thing you ask a guy you just met.
我真的觉得我们该好好想想这里面的因果关系了
I really think we should examine the chain of causality here.
-有必要吗  -事件一
-must we? -event a...
我们那淋浴器下站着个裸体美女
A beautiful woman stands naked in our shower.
事件二  我们开车穿过半个城市到上述那位女性的
Event b... we drive halfway across town to retrieve a television set
前男友住处取回一台电视机
From the aforementioned woman's ex-boyfriend.
提问  在哪个层面上
Query... on what plane of existence
这两个事件哪怕是有半点合理的联系
Is there even a semi-rational link between these events?
她请求我帮她个忙  谢尔顿
She asked me to do her a favor,sheldon.
是啊  这可能是我们这趟旅途最近似的原因了
Yes,well,that may be the proximal cause of our journey,
但其只存在于更高层次原因的对比之下
But we both know it only exists in contradistinction
这点我们都清楚
To the higher level distal cause.
-是什么  -你在用下半身在思考
-which is? -you think with your penis.
从生理上说这是不可能的  还有  你可以不用跟来啊
That's a biological impossibility. and you didn't have to come.
不错  我可以留在那儿看着沃尔维茨勾引佩妮
Right,I could have stayed behind and watch wolowitz try to hit on penny
用俄语  阿拉伯语  波斯语
In russian,arabic and farsi.
为什么她自己不去取回电视机
Why can't she get her own tv?
得了  你知道分手是怎么回事
Come on,you know how it is with breakups.
我不知道...  你也不知道
No,I don't... and neither do you.
我以前跟乔伊斯·金分手过
I broke up with joyce kim.
你没有和乔伊斯·金分手  是她投奔回朝鲜了
You did not break up with joyce kim. she defected to north korea.
去缝补她破碎的心啊
To mend her broken heart.
现在这情况远没那么复杂
This situation is much less complicated.
就谁该得到这台电视的拥有权
There's some kind of dispute between penny and her ex-boyfriend
佩妮和她前男友有过争吵
As to who gets custody of the tv.
她只是不想和他再大吵大闹
She just wanted to avoid having a scene with him.
-所以我们去和他大吵大闹  -不  我们不用和他去吵的
-so we get to have a scene with him? -no,there's not going to be a scene.
我们两个人  他才一个
There's two of us and one of him.
莱纳德  我们两个甚至搬不动一台电视
Leonard,the two of us can't even carry a tv.
这么说  你们和莱纳德还有谢尔顿一起在大学里共事?
So,you guys work with leonard and sheldon at the university?
抱歉  你会说英语吗
I'm sorry,do you speak english?
他会说英语  他只是不会同女人说话
He speaks english. he just can't speak to women.
真的?  为什么?
Really? why?
他是个怪才吧
He's kind of a nerd.
喝果汁?
Juice box?
我来说话
I'll do the talking.
-谁?  -你好  我是莱纳德  这是谢尔顿
-yeah? -hi,I'm leonard,this is sheldon.
-你好  -我刚说...
-hello. -what did I just--
-我们是来拿佩妮的电视机的  -你们走吧
-we're here to pick up penny's tv. -get lost.
好的  抱歉打扰了
Okay,thanks for you time.
我们不能就这样放弃了
We're not going to give up just like that.
莱纳德  电视机在楼上
Leonard,the tv's in the building.
我们已经被阻止进入大楼了  因此  我们没戏了
We've been denied access to the building,ergo,we are done.
我很抱歉  如果我当初遇到点小麻烦就放弃的话
Excuse me. if I were to give up on the first little hitch,
我永远也不会在宇宙大爆炸之后
I never would have identified the fingerprints of string theory
成功验证弦理论了
In the aftermath of the big bang.
我道歉  你准备怎么做?
My apologies. what's your plan?
能目睹你动脑 实在很荣幸
It's just a privilege to watch your mind at work.
不会吧  我们的智商加起来有360呢
Come on,we have a combined iq of 360.
我们应该有办法想出如何进那该死的楼
We should be able to figure out how to get into a stupid building.
你认为她们的智商加起来有多少?
What do you think their combined iq is?
快把门抵住
Just grab the door!
就这里了
This is it.
我来说话
I'll do the talking.
想得不错  我来当打手
Good thinking. I'll just be the muscle.
什么事
Yeah?
我是莱纳德  这是谢尔顿
I'm leonard,this is sheldon.
刚对讲机里的
From the intercom.
你们到底是怎么进来的?
How the hell did you get in the building?
我们是科学家
We're scientists.
告诉他我们的智商
Tell him about our iq.
-莱纳德  -怎么?
-leonard... -what?
-那裤子是我妈买给我的  -对不起
-my mom bought me those pants. -i'm sorry.
你得打电话跟她说一下
You're going to have to call her.
谢尔顿  拖你下水了  真的很抱歉
Sheldon,I am so sorry I dragged you through this.
没关系  这不是我的第一条裤子  也不会是最后一条
It's okay. it wasn't my first pantsing and it won't be my last.
关于我的动机你说得没错
And you were right about my motives.
我是指望和佩妮能建立关系
I was hoping to establish a relationship with penny
或许有一天可以和她上床
That might have someday led to sex.
你倒是脱下了我的裤子
Well,you got me out of my pants.
好了  反正我买到教训了
Anyway,I've learned my lesson.
她和我不是一类人  我跟她玩完了
She's out of my league,I'm done with her.
我有工作要干  有一天我会赢得诺贝尔奖
Got my work,one day I'll win the nobel prize
然后孤单地死去
And then I'll die alone.
不要这么想  你不会孤单地死去的
Don't think like that. you're not going to die alone.
谢谢  谢尔顿  你真是好朋友
Thank you,sheldon. you're a good friend.
而且你肯定不会拿诺贝尔奖的
And you're certainly not going to win a nobel prize.
这是我搜寻猎物后最喜欢的交付地之一
This is one of my favorite places to kick back after a quest.
这里的麦酒太棒了
They have a great house ale.
好酷的老虎
Cool tiger.
是的  我从第十级开始就有了
Yeah,I've had him since level ten.
他叫扣扣
His name is buttons.
如果你有自己的游戏人物
Anyway,if you had your own game character
也许我们可以一起  出去搜寻猎物
We could hang out,maybe go on a quest.
听上去很有意思
That sounds interesting.
你会考虑一下?
You'll think about it?
我没办法不去想它
I don't think I'll be able to stop thinking about it.
很成功啊
Smooth.
我们回来了
We're home.
上帝啊  发生什么事了
My god,what happened?
你前男友要我们代他问好
Well,your ex-boyfriend sends his regards
其他我想已经可以一目了然了
And I think the rest is fairly self-explanatory.
真对不起  我真的以为如果你们替我过去
I'm so sorry. I really thought if you guys went instead of me
他不会这么混蛋的
He wouldn't be such an ass.
不  你这样假设是有道理的
No,it was a valid hypothesis.
有道理的?  你怎么回事?
That was a valid...? what is happening to you?
真的  你们这么努力  这么帮忙  真是太谢谢了
Really,thank you so much for going and trying,you're just...
你们真的太好了  真的
You're so terrific. really.
你们去把衣服穿好
Why don't you put some clothes on,
我去拿我的包  晚饭我请  好吗?
I'll get my purse,and dinner is on me,okay?
-真的?  好啊  -谢谢
-really? great. -thank you.
你跟她还没玩完  是吗?
You're not done with her,are you?
我们的孩子会既聪明又美丽
Are babies will be smart and beautiful.
想象力更是不言而喻
Not to mention imaginary.
-佩妮  你觉得泰国菜如何  -可以啊
-is thai food okay with you,penny? -sure.
我们不能去吃泰国菜
We can't have thai food,
-中午我们吃了印度菜  -又怎样呢
-we had indian for lunch. -so?
-他们都是用咖喱烹饪的  -又怎样呢
-they're both curry-based cuisines. -so?
从烹饪学角度来说  这是过剩的
It would be gastronomically redundant.
我估计以后无论什么我们都需要跟这个女孩解释一下
I can see we're going to have to spell out everything for this girl.
你觉得呢  拉杰?
Any ideas,raj?
到林克街左转  直接去科罗拉多
Turn left on lake street and head up to colorado.
我知道一个寿司吧  那里还有卡拉OK
I know a wonderful little sushi bar that has karaoke.
听上去挺有意思
That sounds like fun.
宝贝  别被我迷住了
baby don't get hook up on me
我不知道在整个世界范围内你的成功概率有多少
I don't know what your odds are in the world as a whole,
不过就这辆车子里的人来说  你还是很有希望的
But as far as the population of this car goes,